goststat.com 2016-02-29

# PRIVACY POLICY | Goststat

Privacy Policy – Goststat

MBR Informatics pvt Ltd is a leading actor within the IT security field and makes every effort to protect the privacy of the users of the Goststat web sites (the “Goststat Sites”). The overall purpose with this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) is to advise you (“You”) of what type of personal information that Goststat collects about You as a result of Your use of the Goststat Sites, if any, and describe the limited purposes for which Goststat uses, processes and shares such collected information.

**Collection of Personal Information**

Goststat may request that You provide certain Personal Information in order to use certain services or pursue certain activities on the Goststat Sites, as further specified below. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy “Personal Information” means any information that identifies You as an individual, including but not limited to Your name, postal address and e-mail address. Goststat does not collect any sensitive Personal Information through the Goststat Sites, such as social security number, credit card number or other personally identifiable financial information, however please note that certain of Goststat ‘s service providers and co-operation partners may collect such sensitive Personal Information in connection with activities that are initiated by You through the Goststat Sites, as further detailed below. Goststat is, with the exceptions set out below, the sole owner of the information collected through the Goststat Sites and Goststat will not share such information with any third party unless to the extent and for the purposes as specified by this Privacy Policy.

  * If You wish to participate in certain of the forums, centers and communities made available on the Goststat Sites such as My Goststat and the Goststat Beta Center, Goststat may ask You to register a user account and to provide certain Personal Information which Goststat from time to time requires for Your participation in these forums and communities, including but not limited to Your e-mail address.
  * If You have subscribed to Goststat newsletters, press releases and/or special offers through the Goststat Sites or elsewhere, Goststat will ask You to provide certain Personal Information such as Your e-mail address.
  * If You submit an on-line order for any Goststat software products or services through a Goststat online store or through a Goststat third party sales partner You will be asked to provide certain Personal Information in order to be able to complete the purchase, such as name, postal address, e-mail and credit card details. Please note in this respect that the Goststat on-line stores are operated by third party e-commerce service providers, that such e-commerce service providers will own any Personal Information that You provide in connection with the purchase of Goststat software products and/or services and that such e-commerce providers’ privacy policies will apply for any Personal Information that You provide through the Goststat online stores.
  * If You request online support for any Goststat software products through the Goststat Sites, Goststat will ask You to register a user account and to provide information necessary in order for Goststat to provide appropriate support services, such as e-mail address, country of residence, license number, hardware and the type of problems that You are experiencing. Please note in this respect that certain support services offered via the Goststat Sites are not provided by Goststat, but by Goststat recommended support service providers.
  * If You wish to take part of certain Goststat or third party offers for products and/or services at the Goststat Sites, You may be asked to provide certain Personal Information such as name and e-mail address. Please note that, for certain offers from Goststat partners, You will be redirected to the Goststat partners’ sites to take part in the offer, in which case the Goststat partners’ will own any Personal Information provided by You in relation to such offer and the Goststat partners’ privacy policies will apply for any Personal Information that You may provide.
  * If you decide to enroll into the Goststat referral program, You will be asked to provide information such as the first & the last name as well as your email address. This information will be used for tracking and communicating back to You the completion status of your referrals.

Please note that Goststat does not control, does not review and has no responsibility for the privacy policies of its service providers or co-operation partners. Goststat therefore encourage You to read such service providers’ and/or partners’ privacy policies thoroughly before You submit any Personal Information to such third party service providers and partners.

Goststat will receive certain of Your Personal Information from the aforementioned third party service providers (excluding sensitive Personal Information such as social security number, credit card details and other personally identifiable financial information) and such Personal Information will thereafter be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Further, Goststat will receive certain Personal Information (excluding sensitive Personal Information such as social security number, credit card details and other personally identifiable financial information) from distribution partners and resellers of Goststat software products in which case such Personal Information will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

You decide in Your sole discretion whether You want to proceed with any activity on the Goststat Sites that requires You to provide Personal Information to Goststat and Goststat ‘s service providers or partners. Please note, however, that if You choose not to provide the requested information You may not be entitled to pursue the requested activity or otherwise use the full functionality of the Goststat Sites.

**Use of Personal Information**

Goststat will use and process Your Personal Information solely for the following purposes:

  * If You have registered an account for any Goststat forum, centers or communities, including but not limited to My Goststat and the Goststat Beta Center, Goststat will use the Personal Information provided through the user account in order to e.g. provide the relevant services; alert You of events relating to Your participation in the relevant forum, center or community; contact You relating to administrative tasks relating to Your user account and send password reminders upon Your request.
  * If You have chosen to subscribe to Goststat newsletters, press releases and/or special offers, Goststat will use the Personal Information that You provide in connection with such subscription for the purpose of providing You with such newsletter, press releases and/or special offers. You can unsubscribe from the Goststat newsletters, press releases and/or special offers at any time by using the[unsubscribe form](http://www.lavasoft.com/email_subscribe.php).
  * If You have purchased Goststat software products, Goststat will use Your Personal Information to provide You with important user information relating to the specific Goststat software products that You hold a license for as well as to provide You with license specific information, including but not limited to notices on when the license is about to expire etc.
  * If You have registered an account at the Goststat Support Forum, Goststat will use the Personal Information provided through the user account in order to e.g. provide the relevant support services; contact You relating to administrative tasks relating to Your user account and send password reminders upon Your request.
  * If You accept an offer for Goststat or third party products or services on the Goststat Sites, the Personal Information provided by You to Goststat in relation to such offer (if any) will be used for the provision to You of such products or services.
  * If you have enrolled into Goststat Referral Program, the information you provided (first & last name as well as email) will be used for tracking the status of your referrals and communicating it back to You. Your information is secure and confidential. No information will be shared with third parties.

**Public Information**

Please note that any and all information, discussions, opinions, blogs, postings, ideas, feedback and other communications and materials of any kind that You post, upload, submit or otherwise make available within the various forums, centers and communities on the Goststat Sites or elsewhere on the Goststat Sites will be considered public information and will not in any way be treated as confidential information.

**Sharing of Personal Information with Third Parties**

Goststat will not share Your Personal Information with any third party except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or if Goststat receives Your prior permission. Please note in this respect that Goststat uses third party hosting service providers for the provision of the Goststat Sites and that Goststat uses third party service providers for the provision of certain services offered through the Goststat Sites, including but not limited to e-mail marketing campaigns, provisions of Goststat newsletters, press releases and/or special offers.

Goststat shares Personal Information with the aforementioned third party service providers, however the Goststat service providers are required by agreement to keep any and all Personal Information received from Goststat strictly confidential and the service providers have no rights whatsoever to use any such Personal Information in any way other than for the purpose for which it was received by Goststat. Accordingly the service providers are not allowed to use any Personal Information received for direct marketing purposes or to share the Personal Information with any third parties. Further, the Goststat service providers are required to adopt appropriate security measures in order to protect such Personal Information from unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration.

In addition to the above, Goststat may share Your Personal Information if required to do so under applicable laws or regulations.

**Statistical Information**

Goststat may further share with third parties aggregate statistical information, i.e. information which does not identify You as an individual, but refers to certain Goststat users in aggregate. Examples of such aggregate statistical information include the number of users that downloaded a specific product or number of users that clicked on a particular advertisement.

**Security of Personal Information**

Goststat has implemented appropriate security measures in order to protect Your Personal Information, including but not limited to appropriate technical measures to protect Your Personal Information from misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure and alteration. If You have been provided with a password in order to access certain forums, centers and/or communities at the Goststat Sites You are responsible for keeping that password confidential and You should not to reveal that password to any third party.

**Children’s Privacy**

Goststat further recognize the particular importance of protecting the privacy of children and Goststat is committed to protecting children’s privacy on the Internet. Goststat does not generally target children and does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If Goststat would discover that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided Personal Information through the Goststat Sites or if Goststat is contacted by a verifiable parent or legal guardian about his or her child’s participation on the Goststat Sites, Goststat will delete the Personal Information about the child from Goststat’s active user records.

**Links to Other Sites**

On the Goststat Sites You will find various links to the web sites of certain Goststat partners as well as offers for such partners’ products and services which direct You to such partners’ web sites. For the avoidance of any doubt, Goststat is not responsible for the content, business practices or operations of such web sites. Please note that these partners have their own privacy policies. If You link to our cooperation partners’ websites from any of the Goststat Sites we encourage You to read such partners’ privacy policies before You submit any Personal Information on their sites. The presence of a link to Goststat partners’ websites does not constitute or imply Goststat’s endorsement, recommendation, or sponsorship of the content, goods, or services available through, or contained on, such partners’ websites.

**Cookies**

Goststat uses Cookies to understand how the Goststat Sites are being used with the purpose of improving the content and offerings of the Goststat Sites. “Cookies” are minor text files that are placed in Your computer’s browser with the purpose of storing Your preferences. Cookies do not provide Goststat with any Personal Information, however, if you provide Goststat with Personal Information through the Goststat Sites or elsewhere, such Personal Information may be linked to the data stored in the Cookie. Goststat may use Cookies to personalize your experience at the Goststat Sites (e.g. to recognize You by name when you return to our site or to remember at Your request user name and/or password for certain user accounts). Goststat may further use Cookies to create personalized offers for products and/or services.

In addition to the above, Goststat uses Google Analytics, a web analytic service provided by Google, Inc. that uses Cookies in order to analyze how our users use the Goststat Sites. The information generated by such Cookies about Your use of the website (including Your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use the information collected through such Cookies for the purpose of evaluating the use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties when required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate Your IP address with any other data held by Google.

You may refuse Goststat’s use of Cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on Your browser. Please note however, that if You refuse Cookies You may not be able to pursue certain activities at the Goststat Site and/or otherwise use the full functionality of the Goststat Sites.

**Access to and Corrections of Personal Information**

In order to keep Your Personal Information accurate, Goststat depends on You to amend Your user account(s) to include updated contact details. Registered users may update their user accounts by accessing them electronically through the Goststat Sites. If you wish to ascertain which of Your Personal Information Goststat stores and/or to which third parties such stored Personal Information have been provided, please send a written request by email to [support@mbrinformatics.com](mailto:support@mbrinformatics.com) or by mail to the postal address of Goststat provided below. The request which shall be sent to the attention of Goststat’s Privacy Agent shall be signed by You and shall include proof of identification such as Your full name, postal address, e-mail address (including previous e-mail addresses that You have used on the Goststat Sites). Goststat will make reasonable efforts to respond to such requests within one (1) month from receipt thereof, provided however that such request is provided no more frequently than once a year. In the event any incorrect or false Personal Information has been stored relating to You, You may further request Goststat to correct, block or delete any such incorrect or false Personal Information.

Please note that if You request that Goststat delete certain Personal Information relating to You, You may no longer be entitled to continue to pursue certain activities at the Goststat Sites and/or to otherwise use the full functionality of the Goststat Sites.

**Amendments of this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy will be updated by Goststat on a regular basis. We therefore recommend that You check this Privacy Policy periodically for modifications.

**Contact Information**

If You have any questions about this Privacy Policy , don’t hesitate to [contact us](http://www.lavasoft.com/mylavasoft/company/contact).
